Massacre Chapter
Part Six
A Strong Will
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Mei Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
Hi
gu
ra
shi
no
Na
ku
Koro
ni
Kai
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
（北条(ほうじょう)）チッ　通帳の場所―
You better have remembered where the bank account book is before I get off the phone.
電話が終わるまでに
思い出しとかんね
（沙都子(さとこ)）うっ　ハア…　うっ
（足音）
Hello?
Sorry to disturb you.
（原山(はらやま)）お世話になっております
興宮(おきのみや)児童相談所でございます
Okinomiya Child Counseling Center speaking.
Again?
またかいね？
あんたんとこも暇やんなあ
Got nothing better to do?
Sorry.
（原山）
申し訳ございません　沙都子さん
病気でお休みと聞いておりますが
We heard Satoko-san is staying at home due to illness...
...but we wanted to make sure of something ASAP.
大至急
確認したいことがありまして
（北条）何じゃい？
わしが答えたるわ
What?
I already told you, didn't I?
（原山）もう一度 お願いします
Once more, please.
沙都子さんを
電話に出していただけませんか？
Could you put Satoko-san on the phone?
Huh?
ワレえ 今日は えらい強気やんね
You're being awfully agressive today.
Do you refuse to let us talk to Satoko-san?
（原山）
沙都子さんを電話に出されるのを
拒否されますか？
Wait up.
ちょいと待っとれや
風邪で寝てるんを起こすん
I'll go wake her up.
くっ…　ハア ハア…
（北条）うーん…　チッ
ああ めんどくせ
What a pain in the ass...
Hey, Satoko.
おう 沙都子　相談所から電話じゃ
Phone from the Counseling Center.
ハア…　何のかんのあっても
わしら仲良し家族やんね？
No matter what happens...
...we're a happy family, right?
なあ？
Right?
はい
Yes.
If you make me angry...
わしを怒らせると 悟史(さとし)の部屋が
大変なことになってまうのう
...you can say bye bye to Satoshi's room.
Understand?
分かっとるな？
I understand.
分かってますわ
We're a happy family.
仲良しですもの
はい
Hello?
Satoko Houjou-san, right?
（原山）北条沙都子さんですね？
This is Harayama of the Okinomiya Child Counseling Center.
こちらは興宮児童相談所の
原山と申します
Did anything happen since last time?
いかがですか その後は？
Nothing in particular.
特に変わったことは
ございませんわ
（原山）そうですか
え？　ああ はいはい どうぞ
Is that so...
Sure, go ahead.
Hello?
（圭一(けいいち)）もしもし 沙都子か？
俺だ　圭一だ
Satoko?
It's me, Keiichi.
Listen, Satoko.
いいか 沙都子
もう全部 決着がつくぞ
Everything is settled.
The Director of the Counseling Center promised he would protect you the moment you agree.
児童相談所の所長は
お前が“うん”と うなずけば―
即時に保護すると約束した
ヘッ すげえだろ？
Isn't that great!?
園崎(そのざき)家が全部
手回ししてくれたんだ
The Sonozaki family arranged it all.
魅音(みおん)の ばあさんが―
Mion's grandmother went to those lengths for you.
そこまで動いてくれたんだぜ
Save Satoko-chan!!
Right now, over two hundred people from Hinamizawa and Okinomiya have gathered in front of the Counseling Center.
（圭一）今 相談所の外に
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)や興宮から―
200人以上の人が集まってるんだ
They put their festival preparation work aside.
祭りの準備を放り出して―
They're all here to lobby for your release!
お前を助けるための陳情に
集まってくれてる
ヘヘッ　お前に見せてやれないのが
残念だぜ
It's such a shame I can't show you this!
確かに―
Sure...
There were people in Hinamizawa ignoring you and treating you badly just for being the daughter of the Houjou family.
ダム戦争以来 雛見沢では
北条の娘だというだけで―
沙都子を無視したり
冷たくする奴がいた
But you know...
でもな そんなのは
俺が全部 打ち破ってやった
...I shattered that all for you!
雛見沢で お前のことを
いじめようとする奴は―
There's no one left in Hinamizawa who would pick on you anymore!
もう１人もいないんだ
Satoko.
（梨花(りか)）沙都子？　梨花です
It's Rika.
Keiichi and the others put an end to everything.
（梨花）圭一たちが
全部 終わらせてくれたのです
本当に もう雛見沢は
沙都子に意地悪をしないのですよ
Hinamizawa really won't treat you badly anymore.
So even if we go out shopping together...
だから ボクと沙都子が
一緒にお買い物に行っても―
沙都子だけが無視されたりしない
...you will no longer get ignored.
There are no longer people who would make you feel bad.
沙都子に冷たくする人は
もういないのです
そんなのって信じられませんわ
I can't believe something like that.
Yeah...
（梨花）そうね　私も信じられない
Neither can I.
When you were taken away by Teppei...
あなたが
鉄平(てっぺい)に連れ去られた時―
...I gave up thinking it was a fated dead-end.
これは どうにもならない
運命の袋小路なんだと諦めた
But it wasn't fate at all.
でも運命なんてなかった
圭一が打ち破ってみせてくれた
Keiichi showed me how he defeated it.
We have our hands reached out right in front of your eyes.
私たちは今 あなたの目の前まで
救いの手を伸ばしてる
あなたが うなずくだけで 手が届く
If you so much as nod, we'll be able to reach you.
でも私(わたくし)
強くならなくちゃいけないんですの
But I...
...have to be strong.
To simply withstand this may be your idea of being strong...
（梨花）
あなたは耐えることが強さだと
思っているようだけど それは違う
...but that's not right.
Remember.
思い出しなさい
Remember Satoshi as he protected you from your aunt.
あの 叔母からあなたを
かばってくれていた悟史の姿を
沙都子　あなたの
すぐ後ろにいるんでしょ
Satoko.
He's right behind you, isn't he?
Yes.
Look at that man's face.
その男の顔を見なさい
その恐ろしくて醜悪な顔を
That terrifying, hideous face.
そして その恐ろしさに―
And realize Satoshi's courage for boldly standing up against that terror.
敢然と立ち向かった悟史の勇敢さに
気づきなさい
If you are trying to atone for what happened to Satoshi...
もしあなたが悟史に対する罪を
償おうとするならば―
それは助けを求めないことじゃない
...then refusing help is not the right way.
悟史の勇気を 力強さを
受け継ぐことなの
You need to take over Satoshi's courage and strength!
（梨花）それに気づきなさい！
You have to realize that!
（北条）何じゃい？
Hey.
長い電話じゃのう
That's a damn long phone call.
ああん？
Satoko.
（梨花）沙都子
これから受話器を相談所の人に戻す
I will give the phone back to the person from the Counseling Center.
Tell him.
あなたの口で伝えなさい
あなたの勇気を見てるから
Show us your courage.
梨花…　うう…
Rika...
Hello?
（原山）もしもし 原山です
もう一度 確認いたします
Harayama speaking.
I will ask for confirmation once more.
Have there been any problems since you started living with Teppei-san?
鉄平さんとの その後の生活は
問題ありませんか？
Well, Satoko-san?
どうですか？　沙都子さん
（沙都子）…けて
He...
Excuse me?
（原山）はい？
もう一度 お願いします
Come again, please.
私を…
Help...
私を助けて！
Help me!
You fucking moron!
おんどりゃあ！
裏切りおったんな！
You betrayed me!
うっ…　あんたなんか大っ嫌い！
出てって！　ここから出てって！
I hate you!
Get out!
Get out of this house!
ここは私と にーにーの家ですのよ
私たち家族の家ですのよ
This house belongs to me and Nii-nii!
This is our family house!
I despise you!
あんたなんか大っ嫌い
あんたなんか出てけー！
Get the hell out!
（北条）この野郎！
（沙都子）わあ！　うっ…
You little bitch!
What's with that look!?
何じゃい その目は!?
前歯 へし折られたいんか
（沙都子）うっ…
Want me to bash out those teeth!?
（北条）くっ…　ふんっ
（沙都子）ああっ！
ふんっ
（戸をたたく音）
Teppei Houjou!
（警官）北条鉄平！
（北条）ん？
（警官）ここを開けろ　警察だ！
（北条）な… 何やねん
Open the door!
This is the police!
The hell!?
（警官）早く開けんか！
打ち破って入るぞ こらあ！
Open up now!
We're gonna break the door open!
You're kidding me...
（北条）ウソやろお!?
（戸が開く音）
（圭一）もしもし 沙都子？
Hello?
Satoko?
沙都子！
（大石(おおいし)）大丈夫ですよ 前原(まえばら)さん
Satoko!
Don't worry, Maebara-san.
（圭一）あ…
（大石）先ほど―
The police just rushed into the Houjou residence.
北条家に警察が突入しました
えっ？
（大石）とにかく―
Anyway...
If everything is settled now, be sure to dismiss that group down there.
一件落着でしたら
下の集団 解散してくださいよ
フーン
（一同）あ…
While Ooishi was listening to Satoko on the phone...
大石は沙都子の電話を
聞くのと同時に―
...he was contacting someone over his radio.
無線で どこかへ
連絡していましたのです
I see...
（詩音(しおん)）そっか　リナ殺しの件で
警察が張ってたわけだ
The police were already on his back due to that Rina murder incident.
（圭一）リナ？
Rina?
（魅音）
まあ いろいろあるらしいよ
Well...
Seems a lot of things happen...
...in the adult world.
大人の世界は
（詩音）フフッ
Satoko!
（圭一）沙都子！
（沙都子）あ…
It was an incredibly long day.
（圭一）ものすごく長い１日だった
（圭一）この１週間の間に
俺たちは結束し―
In the past week...
...we stood united...
闘いを乗り越え 勝ち取った
...overcame the fight...
...and achieved victory.
沙都子を冷遇してきたダム戦争の
号令を 俺たちは打ち破り―
We shattered the dam war tyranny against Satoko...
...and took back our peaceful days.
平和な日常を
この手に取り戻したんだ
（圭一）そして明日は綿流し
雛見沢 最大のお祭りの日だ
And tomorrow will be Watanagashi.
The day of Hinamizawa's greatest festival.
All right!
（魅音）
よっしゃー！　んじゃ まずは
たこ焼き早食い競争！
First up is the takoyaki eating contest!
（レナ）はう～！　負けないよ～！
I won't lose!
This is the first time I've seen such a fun Watanagashi festival.
（羽入(はにゅう)）
こんな楽しい綿流しのお祭りは
初めて見ますのです
そうね　私も初めてよ
You're right.
It's a first for me too.
私は分かった
（羽入）あ…
I understand now.
The meaning of fighting against fate.
運命に あらがうことの意味
そして その戦い方
As well as the way to go about it.
Rika!
梨花ー！
I will never yield to fate ever again.
（梨花）二度と私は運命に屈しない
Never again!
二度と
今日は罰ゲーム２倍ですのよ
Today we'll have a double punishment game.
（笑い声）
（梨花）負けられないのです
I can't lose!
（富竹(とみたけ)）
ああ そんなことを言ってたね
アッハッハッ…
You said something like that, didn't you?
But why would me and Takano-san be killed?
でも どうして僕と鷹野(たかの)さんが
殺されなきゃならないんだい？
（鷹野）あらあ
My...
To think we would be chosen as victims in the fifth year of the curse...
私たちが５年目の祟(たた)りの犠牲者に
選ばれるなんて―
That's quite an honor!
名誉な話よ　フフフッ
I will tell you once more.
（梨花）もう一度 言いますです
Tomitake will die by clawing out his throat.
富竹は
のどをかきむしって死にます
Takano will burn to death in a drum can deep in the mountains.
鷹野は どこか遠くの山奥
ドラム缶の中で焼け死にますのです
Claw out my throat?
（富竹）のどをかきむしるって…
That would be Level 5...
それはレベル５
末期症状のことかい？
The terminal stage of the disease.
Don't worry.
大丈夫だよ
僕はちゃんと予防接種を受けてるし
I've vaccinated myself.
（鷹野）
それとも夢のお告げかしら？
Or was this a prophecy from your dreams?
あ…
（鷹野）大丈夫よ　フフッ
Don't worry.
If worse comes to worst...
万が一の時は ジロウさんが
守ってくれるもの　ねえ？
...Jirou-san will protect me.
Right?
え？　あ…　アッハッハッ…
But you will die.
でも死ぬのです
If you two die...
富竹と鷹野が死んだら
誰がボクを守ってくれるのですか？
...who will protect me?
If we ever were to die...
（鷹野）万が一 私たちが
死ぬようなことになっても―
...the Yamainu will guard you.
山狗(やまいぬ)があなたを警護するわ
Will the Yamainu really protect me?
（梨花）山狗は本当に
ボクを守ってくれるのでしょうか
No need to worry.
心配しないで
Their protection is even more robust than that of Director Irie's.
入江(いりえ)所長の警護よりも
厳重なくらいよ
うん　僕らも
今夜は気をつけるようにするよ
We'll be careful tonight.
２人きりの時に
襲われるのだと思いますです
I believe you will get attacked when you two are alone.
So please don't wander off somewhere together.
だから 今夜２人きりになっては
ダメなのです
あらあら やいているのかしら？
（富竹）あ…
Oh my...
Could you be jealous?
おませさんねえ
Such a precocious girl.
梨花ちゃん！
Rika-chan!
（梨花）２人が聞き入れないことは
分かってた
I knew they wouldn't listen to me.
But I'm not going to give up!
でも 諦めるもんか
Where did you hear that?
（大石）それを
どこで聞いたんですか？
I happened to pick it out from the crowd.
（梨花）人混みで
偶然 耳にしたのです
I didn't see their faces, though...
話をしていた人の顔は
見えなかったのですが…
（大石）うーん
富竹さんと鷹野さんが…
Tomitake-san and Takano-san, huh...
One will die, and one will disappear.
１人が死んで １人が消える
Taking into account that it would be the fifth instance of the curse...
確かに ５年目の祟りとしては
あってもおかしくなさそうですねえ
...it doesn't seem implausible.
They said they would attack them on the road between Hinamizawa and Okinomiya.
襲うなら 雛見沢と興宮の
間の道だとも言っていましたのです
Okay.
分かりました　では その近辺に
車を１台 張りつかせましょう
Let's assign a patrol car to that vicinity, then.
ん…　ありがとうなのです
Thank you.
誰もボクのことを
信じてくれないので―
Since no one believed me, I was about to lose it.
困っていたところなのです
The police is there to believe you.
それを信じるのが警察です
If nothing happens, we should just be glad no one got hurt, right?
何事もなければ むしろ
無事を喜ぶべきじゃないですか？
（大石）ンッフフフ～
（梨花）あ…
Tomitake-san and Takano-san will be killed!?
（魅音）富竹さんと鷹野さんが!?
（梨花）はい なのです
Yes.
（圭一）
オヤシロさまの祟りってやつか
By Oyashiro-sama's curse?
You can never be too cautious, right?
（レナ）用心に越したことは
ないんじゃないかな　かな
そうですわね
That's right.
Okay.
よし　ひと晩中ってのは
無理だけど―
We can't keep it up all night...
せめて 祭りが終わるまでの間
護衛といくか
...but we'll tag along with them until the end of the festival.
人が近くにいれば おいそれと
手出しできねえだろうしな
I doubt anyone would attack if there are other people close by.
（圭一）よし
まずは富竹さんたちを捜そう
Okay!
Let's find Tomitake-san and Takano-san first.
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
Thanks, everyone.
（富竹）ありがとう みんな
We'll be okay now.
ここまで来れば大丈夫だよ
I'll bring Jirou-san back in my car, so don't worry.
あとは私の車でジロウさんを
送っていくから心配いらないわ
Right.
そうだね　私たちも
そろそろ帰らないと
We should go back soon as well.
Yeah.
Thanks for expressing your concern for us.
気を利かせてくれて ありがとう
You two really have to be on your guard.
２人とも 本当に用心するのですよ
Rika.
梨花　心配しすぎですわよ
You're worrying too much.
See you later then, everyone.
じゃあまたね　みんな
次に会うのは秋頃かな？
The next time I'll see you all will be around autumn.
If we don't get killed, that is.
私たちが殺されなければ… ね
それじゃあ みんな
おやすみなさい
Well then...
...good night everyone.
んじゃ行こっか
（圭一）おう
Let's go?
Sure.
Good night.
（詩音）おやすみなさい
Please tell Director Irie to undertake Rika-chan's examinations thoroughly.
（富竹）
入江所長に 梨花ちゃんの検査を
念入りに行ったほうがよいと―
伝えておいてください
It'll be a disaster if something happens to her.
梨花ちゃんに何かあったら
大変なことになるからね　あ…
（鷹野）あ…　ねえ ジロウさん
Hey, Jirou-san?
I have something very serious to tell you.
とてもまじめな話があるの
聞いてくださる？
Will you listen?
あ…　どうしたんだい？
What's wrong?
I'm really surprised.
驚いているのよ　あの子には
神通力があるのかもしれないってね
That girl might just have supernatural powers.
I...
私 あなたのことが好きよ
...like you.
あ…　急にどうしたんだい？
What's wrong with you all of a sudden?
It's finally time.
（鷹野）
いよいよなの　もうじきなのよ
Very soon now.
The day my dream will come true has arrived.
（鷹野）私の夢がかなう日が
やってくるの
Your dream?
（富竹）君の夢？
I've told you about it, haven't I?
（鷹野）
話したこと あったわよね？
Or don't you remember the things I tell you in bed?
それともベッドの上で話したことは
記憶に残らないのかしら？　フッ
（富竹）あ…　覚えてるよ　君の夢
I remember.
About your dream.
The day Oyashiro-sama's curse will come into reality has finally arrived.
いよいよ オヤシロさまの祟りが
現実のものとなる日がやってくる
The day my childhood dream will come true.
私の子供の頃からの
夢がかなう日が…
You don't mean...
まさか…
In fact, I do.
その まさかなの
I knew it...
（鷹野）やっぱり
私より仕事が大事みたいね
You value your work over me.
んっ…　これは何のマネだ！
What is the meaning of this!?
The Hinamizawa Syndrome is like a bomb whose fuse has been lit.
雛見沢症候群は
導火線に火がついた爆弾と同じ
Tokyo ordered you to diffuse this bomb before it explodes.
それが爆発する前に―
東京はあなたに
爆弾を解体することを命じた
But you know...
でもね 東京には―
...there are some people in Tokyo who wish to detonate this bomb.
この爆弾が派手に爆発することを
願っている人もいるの
I don't believe it!
信じられん
You should know the Hinamizawa Syndrome is an extremely dangerous disease!
雛見沢症候群が―
とても危険な病気であることは
君も知ってるはずだ
Indeed.
そうよ
It'll be a disaster if it explodes.
爆発すれば
とても大変なことになる
Which is why Tokyo won't be able to cover up a blunder.
だからこそ東京も
失態を隠しきれない
Were you bribed by those people?
君は その連中に
買収されたと言うのか？
ンフフフッ　どうかしらね
I wonder.
んっ…　小此木(おこのぎ)君！
君も寝返ったのか!?
Okonogi-kun!
Did you double-cross us as well!?
You sure are slow.
ジロウさんも鈍いわねえ
山狗は初めから私の部下よ
The Yamainu were my subordinates from the start.
We were controlling this clinic from the start.
この診療所は
最初から私たちが掌握している
The only ones unaware of it were you and Director Irie.
知らないのは
あなたと入江所長だけよ
ウフッ　ハハハハ…
（富竹）くっ…
Seize him!
（小此木）取り押さえろ
（富竹）んっ…　離せ！
I expected nothing less, Jirou-san.
（鷹野）さすがねえ ジロウさん
Even six people have trouble subduing you.
６人がかりでも
てこずらせるなんて すてきよ
How wonderful.
Hey, Jirou-san.
（鷹野）ねえ ジロウさん
I'm sure you'll refuse, but...
どうせ断るんだろうけど―
私の自己満足のために
もう一度 聞かせて
...let me hear it once more for my own satisfaction.
Won't you become my ally?
どうしても私の味方には
なってくれないのかしら？
Forget it!
ムダだ！　君の仲間にはならない
I'll never be your ally!
フッ　そのひと言が聞きたかったの
That's what I wanted to hear.
So I can do this without regret.
私の未練を断ち切るためにね
What's that injection?
その注射は…
（鷹野）イヤねえ
想像がついているくせに
Oh my...
I'm sure you already know.
It can't be!
（富竹）バカな！
全部 破棄したはずじゃ…
We had disposed of it all!
ウフフッ　残念でした
What a shame for you.
By the way.
The prophylactic medicine you took when you came to Hinamizawa this time around...
今回 あなたが雛見沢に来た時
投与された予防薬はね―
...was actually something different.
実は違ったのよ
Bad boy.
ダメよ　自分に
何の薬が投与されてるのか―
You should confirm what medicine you're taking beforehand.
ちゃんと確認しなくちゃ
アッハハハ…
（鷹野）それでは これより
終末作戦を開始します
We will now commence the terminal operation.
You will wake up soon.
もうじき あなたは目を覚ますわ
その頃には
レベル５の末期を迎えている
By then...
...you will have come down with Level 5, the terminal stage.
After going through psychosis...
あなたは錯乱の揚げ句―
...you will likely meet a pitiful demise.
きっと哀れな死に方を
するでしょうね
そして あなたの異常な死と
私の失踪は―
Then, your abnormal death and my disappearance...
...will be accounted to Oyashiro-sama's curse, leaving an even stronger mark in history.
オヤシロさまの祟りとして
ますます強固なものとなって残る
Jirou-san, to get to be a cornerstone for that...
その礎となれるなんて…
ジロウさん
...is an incredible priviledge.
これは とても名誉なことなのよ
ンッフフフハハハ…
This is Warbler.
（隊員）こちら鶯(うぐいす)
岐阜の工作班より連絡あり
We were contacted by the Gifu Division.
（扉が開く音）
ハア…　おいしい
Delicious.
Excuse me, Major.
（隊員）申し訳ありません　三佐
It seems a problem has arisen at the Gifu Division.
岐阜の工作班で
問題が発生したそうです
A problem?
問題？
The mock corpse they had prepared...
（隊員）
用意していた三佐の偽装死体が
死後24時間ほど経過していたとか
Apparently, around twenty-four hours have elapsed since the time of death...
Oh?
あら　そうすると
どういうことになるのかしら？
And what difference will that make?
（隊員）はっ
三佐は昨日の時点で―
It would mean you had already died yesterday.
すでに亡くなっているということに
なってしまいます
フッハハ　いいわ
その死体を私ということにしなさい
Fine.
Pass that corpse off for me.
（隊員）はっ　しかし…
But...
Oyashiro-sama's messenger, who will bring Hinamizawa to destruction...
（鷹野）雛見沢を滅びに導く
オヤシロさまの使いが―
...attended the festival from beyond the grave.
祭りの当日に死者として歩き回った
ンッハハハ　面白いわ
How interesting.
It it okay?
（隊員）よろしいのですか？
万が一ということも…
If by any chance...
There won't be such a chance.
万が一なんてないわ
Miyo Takano strode across the Watanagashi festival grounds today.
すでに鷹野三四(みよ)は今日 綿流しの
お祭りの会場を闊歩(かっぽ)していたのよ
Even if the autopsy shows that twenty-four have passed since the time of my death...
たとえ検視の結果 死後24時間以上
経ってると出たって―
...those naive idiots will doubt the autopsy report instead.
おめでたい連中は検視結果のほうが
間違ってると思ってくれるわよ
フッハハハハ
Roger.
（隊員）了解
岐阜へその旨 連絡します
I will communicate Gifu those instructions.
（鷹野）あっ ねえ
私の死体は どんな感じなの？
Hey.
What is my corpse like?
It was in the mountains close to the highway...
（隊員）高速道路近くの山中―
ドラム缶の中で発見された
焼死体とのことです
A burnt corpse found inside a drum can.
I see.
なるほど
Looks like she isn't called the reincarnation of Oyashiro-sama for nothing.
オヤシロさまの生まれ変わりは
ダテじゃないってわけね
雛見沢の山狗に 古手(ふるで)梨花の
監視体制を厳重にするように連絡を
Order the Yamainu in Hinamizawa to keep a close guard on Rika Furude.
Roger!
（隊員）了解
（隊員）
失礼します　興宮警察が―
Excuse me.
We intercepted a message from the Okinomiya police that Tomitake's corpse has been discovered.
富竹の遺体を発見したとの無線を
傍受しました
ンフッ　いよいよ始まるわよ
It has finally begun.
ンッフフフ…
（熊谷(くまがい)）初見で見た限り
仏は のどをかきむしっています
On a first look...
...his throat seems to have been clawed out...
...with his own hands.
それも自分の手で
This isn't an ordinary cause of death.
こいつあ まっとうな死に方じゃ
ありませんね
In all likelihood...
十中八九
何だかヤバめな薬物でしょう
...it was due to some sort of drug.
The fifth year, huh...
５年目か
（入江）信じられない
I don't believe it...
あり得ない
It can't be...
It's impossible!
絶対に
（鷹野）もうすぐ すべてが滅ぶ
Soon, everything will fall.
すべてがね
Everything.
ンフッ　ンフフフ…
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Shion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Kuraudo Ooishi
Katsuya Kumagai
Miyo Takano
Jirou Tomitake
Kyousuke Irie
Teppei Houjou
Okonogi
Harayama
Man
Chafuurin
Takuo Kawamura
Miki Itou
Tohru Ookawa
Toshihiko Seki
Katsuhisa Houki
Jurota Kosugi
Katsuhiro Oota
Gen Nakano
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hone no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white tip of the bone...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Toshifumi Kawase
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Chiaki Kon
Akira Iwanaga
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisor
Animation Supervision Assistance
Kyoko Kotani
Shouhei Ohara
Chigai Okado
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
Oh no, oh no!
（羽入）大変 大変なのです～！
（梨花）どうしたのですか？
What happened?
The evil hand of capitalism has reached Hinamizawa!
（羽入）雛見沢にも
資本主義の魔の手が伸びるのです
Evil hand?
（梨花）魔の手？
It seems a high-rise resort condominium will be built here!
（羽入）
超高層リゾートマンションが
建つらしいのです
Don't worry!
（梨花）大丈夫　雛見沢には
ダム建設反対運動で養った―
As a result of the dam opposition movement...
...Hinamizawa has a bond of knowledge, courage and blood!
知識と勇気と血の結束があるのです
That will protect Hinamizawa again!
今度も それで
雛見沢を守るのです　おー！
...futhermore, residents of Hinamizawa who gave their approval...
（羽入）なお賛同してくれた
雛見沢の住人には―
...will be allowed to move in for a special discount price, it seems.
大特価 格安価格で
入居させてくれるらしいのです
Magnificent!
（梨花）すばらしいのです！
Who is it that opposes this plan?
どこの どいつが
反対してるのですか？
In times a change of image is necessary for Hinamizawa...
雛見沢も変わらなければ
いけないという時に…
Someone like that should suffer Oyashiro-sama's curse!
そんな奴は
オヤシロさまの祟りなのです！
（羽入）は…　はう～
Next time, the Massacre Chapter, Part Seven.
（梨花）次回　皆殺し編 其の七
「雛見沢症候群」
"The Hinamizawa Syndrome."
So this is what human nature is like...
（羽入）人間なんて
こんなものなのです…
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Massacre Chapter
Part Seven
The Hinamizawa Syndrome